ALLISON LANG

EMEA · allisonlangproduction@gmail.com · www.linkedin.com/in/allisonlang/ <u>UI Portfolio</u> · <u>Production Portfolio</u>

Spunky UI / UX Designer with a background of 10+ years of project managing and a fiery commitment to apply the meticulous attention to detail and problem solving skills acquired after managing over 100+ projects.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Sanical Health - Remote (Freelance)

Nov 2023 – Present

UI / UX Designer

- Consulted a health tech start up on their mobile and web UI, brand guidelines, design system, market analysis and user personas increasing engagement and decreasing user frustration.
- Led the redesign of wireframes and prototypes, incorporating user feedback and industry best practices and rebuilt new key screens for the launch and rebranding in Jan 2024.

Allison Lang Production - Worldwide (Freelance)

May 2015 – Apr 2023

Creative Project Manager / Producer

- Successfully produced 100+ projects which included budgeting, negotiating contracts, managing teams of 60+ people, handling communication with stakeholders and overseeing post production despite tight deadlines.
- Able to remain calm while working under pressure which in return led to repeat clients such as Vice, Gore-Tex, Mercedes, Nike, VW and much more.

Bonaparte Films GmbH - Berlin, Germany (Contract)

Sep 2021 – Apr 2023

Head of Photo & Film Producer

- Scouted artists and launched a new photo department in Jan 2022 which was composed of 8
 artists in which I produced shoots for them in Germany, Slovenia, Italy and Portugal for
 brands such as Bulgari, V-Zug, Wey and VW.
- Brought the work in-house instead of outsourcing using external agencies which in turn created more profit for the company.
- Curated and produced a gallery show and other various events for marketing purposes.

Sportstech GmbH - Berlin, Germany (Full-time)

Mar 2021 - Jul 2021

Senior Project Manager / Producer

- Restructured the creative department which included recruiting a new team to help execute photo and video shoots resulting in 3 high quality premium shoots with higher output.
- Convinced the CEO to expand the production budget by 40% in order to get a better ROI.

RECENT PROJECTS

CLIQUp Social

Dec 2023 - Present

UI/UX Designer

- Collaborated closely with the product designer to spearhead the development of the new 'Organizer" platform for a social app, revolutionizing the events and meet-ups experience for users while increasing engagement.
- Researched and analyzed UI trends and user preferences, providing recommendations to improve user experience in time for the relaunch in Feb 2024.

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry School - Berlin, Germany Apr 2023 - Nov 2023

Certificate in User Interface Design Specialization in Front End Development

Rochester Institute of Technology - New York Aug 2013 - Jun 2015

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Advertising & Photography Minored in Marketing

University of California - Santa Barbara Aug 2011 - Jun 2013

Majored in Communications

SKILLS

• UI Design • International Project Management

∙ UX Design∙ Visual Design

Mock Ups
 Product Development

· Prototypes · Copy Editing

• Design Systems • User Research & Flows

· Front End Development (HTML, CSS, JS) · Content Creation

TOOLS

FigmaSketchAdobeWrike

· Miro · Asana

LANGUAGES

- · English Native
- · Spanish B1
- · German A2